Filippos Christianos

London, UK | filippos.christianos@gmail.com | fchristianos.com | linkedin.com/in/fchristianos

Summary

Research Scientist at Huawei, working on LLMs and Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning. Co-author of the Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning textbook published by *The MIT Press*. Published in *NeurIPS, ICML*, and other top-tier conferences and journals (950+ citations, h-index=9).

Experience

Research Scientist, Huawei - London, UK

2023 - present

- Led a team project to develop an LLM-powered modular agent framework capable of interacting and learning from various environments (e.g., operating systems or web browsers). *Fine-tuned LLMs* (with PyTorch and HuggingFace) using *SFT and RL* to improve the agent's performance in those environments.
- Designed and trained a *Decision Transformer* to solve the PCB placement problem on real-world data.

Research Scientist, Intern, NVIDIA – San Francisco, California (remote)

May - Dec. 2022

• Developed and published (*ICRA 2023*) a novel method for generating plausible *autonomous vehicle (AV)* trajectories in occluded spaces using *variational autoencoders*.

Research Assistant, ENECIA - Athens, Greece

2017 - 2018

• Collaborated with UC Berkeley researchers in a startup environment to create power-consumption prediction models, employing *Gaussian processes*, *ARIMA*, *and similarity-based* methods.

Education

University of Edinburgh, PhD in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning

2019 - 2023

- Used reinforcement learning algorithms (e.g., *PPO, DQN, SAC*) to develop novel multi-agent methods. Published as first author in 2x *NeurIPS, ICML*, and *TMLR*. Supervised by Dr Stefano Albrecht and examined by Dr Frans Oliehoek.
- Was the *Teaching Assistant* of the MSc-level course on reinforcement learning. Led the lecture sessions covering Deep Reinforcement Learning, and designed the coursework assignment.

University of Edinburgh, MScR in Robotics and Autonomous Systems

2018 - 2019

• Awarded Distinction. Courses on Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, and Robotics.

Technical University of Crete, BSc & intgr. MSc (5 yrs) in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2009 - 2016

• Thesis was awarded full marks (10/10) and led to peer-reviewed publication. Studied Computer Science, Electronic, and Telecommunications with a focus on Artificial Intelligence, Game theory, and Multi-Agent Systems.

Selected Publications – Google Scholar

Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning: Foundations and Modern Approaches Co-author — Textbook by The MIT Press.	2024
Pareto Actor-Critic for Equilibrium Selection in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning Joint first author — In Transactions on Machine Learning Research (TMLR).	2023
Benchmarking Multi-Agent Deep Reinforcement Learning Algorithms in Cooperative Tasks Joint first author — In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS).	2021
Scaling Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning with Selective Parameter Sharing First author — In International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML).	2021
Shared Experience Actor-Critic for Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning First author — In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS).	2020

Skills And Additional Experience

Programming: Python, C/C++, JS, Bash | PyTorch, HuggingFace, PyTorch Lightning, NumPy, pandas.

Invited Talks and Seminars: Berkeley Multi-Agent Seminar Group (2022), UoE (2020 – 2023), Motion2AI (2023).

Guest Lectures: University College London (2023), KTH Royal Institute of Technology (2024).